## **David Perich**

🗣 Melbourne, Australia 🛛 davidnperich@gmail.com 🤘 www.davidperich.com

## **Profile**

I'm a full stack software engineer in Melbourne, Victoria with experience in Node/JavaScript, Ruby/Rails, React/Redux, Docker, Kafka, and PostgreSQL. I am the co-creator of Venice 🛽 , an open-source framework for deploying and managing event-stream processing pipelines for small applications.

## **Professional Experience**

01/2020 - present Melbourne, Australia **Venice,** Co-Creator | Software Engineer □

- Developed a containerised back-end infrastructure with Docker to streamline the configuration and deployment of stream processing pipelines to a few simple commands.
- Created a Node.js CLI to abstract and streamline the setup and management of eventstream processing pipeline.
- Wrote bash scripts to automate pipeline startup, add conditional configurations, and to address race conditions between components in the pipeline.
- Developed event producers in Python and Ruby as motivating examples
- Testing pipeline throughput and latency on cloud services (AWS/DO)
- Analysed event-stream processing eco-system to determine best practices, as well as optimal components and configurations for small applications.
- Co-wrote engineering case study on the development of Venice https://veniceframework.github.io/

06/2018 - 12/2019Melbourne, Australia Self Employed, Full-Stack Web Software Developer

Built an extensive number of personal and open source web applications including:

- a project management app similar to Trello with React/Redux and Rails
- a social news and discussion application with Rails, PostgreSQL, and JavaScript
- a personal task management app with Sinatra, PostgreSQL, and Handlebars.js
- an app for searching historical AFL data with Sinatra, PostgreSQL and Javascript.

10/2016 - 12/2019Perth, Australia

Knowledge Society, Senior Consultant

- Led innovation projects for clients in government, education, insurance sectors.
- Led data analytics capability, translating data into actionable insights for major projects.
- Other responsibilities: agile project management, workshop facilitation, data management.

## Education

Launch School, 06/2018 - 11/2019

Remote Software Engineering & Full-stack Web Development

10/2015 - 07/2017 University of Western Australia, Perth, WA Graduate Certificate Social Impact

08/2008 - 12/2010Cardinal Stritch University, Bachelor International Business

Milwaukee, WI

**Skills** 

Front End **Back End** 

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React/Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, Sinatra, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js SQL, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs

AWS, Kafka, Docker, Git/Github, Linux, Docker-Compose, Agile